EVAN DANA

JavaScript Developer Boston, MA

evandana.com

@evandana
mevandana

Front-End Manager / UI Lead Developer with a focus on architecting successful web experiences. Approaches challenges with engaging energy and passion, engineering efficient tooling, processes, and organization to benefit the project and team. Articulate technical and cross-domain communication enhanced by design background.

CODE HIGHLIGHTS

PMC Auction App

https://auction-demo.firebaseapp.com

ReactJS 15.1.x, Redux, websockets, Firebase.io, Material-UI, Google OAuth, ES2015, Babel, Domain Modeling

From concept through development to processing results, this live-bidding auction web app exceeded expectations for learning experiences and funds raised. Working with one other developer, we started with domain models, UX whiteboarding, framework choices, and hosting discussions.

- · Live bidding using websockets, ReactJS, and Redux
- Secure sign-in using Google OAuth
- · Enforced bidding rules
- Database and hosting using Firebase.io (experimented with AWS)

Previous evandana.com

https://github.com/evandana/website-2012

D3.JS, PHP, JavaScript, XML, XSLT, HTML5, CSS3, InDesign XML Workflow

- XML and XSLT drove print (InDesign) and web (PHP) résumé workflows.
- Featured a D3.js interactive graph that highlighted my capabilities in web development, leadership, and design.
- Responsive, mobile-friendly and quick-to-load.
- Linked to page with example code demonstrating and annotating current tech (at the time): HTML5, jQUERY, CSS3 & LESS, XML, PHP.

EDUCATION HISTORY

Rochester Institute of Technology ROCHESTER, NY

Bachelor, Industrial Design | 2001–2005

BFA in Industrial Design, GPA 3.84, highest honors. AAS in Graphic Design. Concentration in conversational French. Technical concentrations in Mechanical and Manufacturing Technology.

Harvard Extension School CAMBRIDGE, MA

Mobile Operating Systems and Applications | 2013–2013

Deep dive into hardware and software underlying Android and iOS operating sytems. Covered spectrum of mobile landscape and considerations for design/development of web, native wrappers, and native apps. Final project: Android "deck of cards" workout app.

Coursera.org STANFORD UNIVERSITY ONLINE 2012–2013

Enriching and expanding skills and understanding with classes: Introduction to Python & Model Thinking & Software Engineering for SaaS. Courses include homework, lectures, and quizzes/exams. Topics covered: Python, Ruby on Rails, SQL, Amazon Web Services, version control with GIT, and cloud deployment with Heroku. Earned a certificate of completion for listed classes.

WORK HISTORY

Publicis.Sapient | Sapient Consulting BOSTON, MA

Sr. Interactive Developer, L2 | 2013-Present

ES2015, AngularJS 1.x, Aurelia, Agile, Atomic Design, BEM, JSPM, NodeJS, Continuous Integration, Hexagonal Architecture (server-side), Domain-Driven Development, Domain Modeling

UI Lead and front-end developer with aptitude for team dynamics: group coordination, process efficiencies, and individual development. Awarded recognition for Client-Focused Delivery after client feedback on project when leading FED with recently self-taught technology.

Years of experience in UI lead role, conducting engaging technical presentations, and as technical liason for client and internal domain teams. Enforced code quality using best practices such as John DePapa's style guide and BEM on both Agile and Atomic approach projects. Self-motivated and driven as exemplified by creation of D3.js library during bench time and initiation of effective team-building program. Advocate for code stability through unit, integration, functional, or automated visual-diff testing.

Putnam Investments BOSTON, MA

Javascript UI Developer | 2012–2013

JavaScript (jQuery, Highcharts), CSS, HTML, Backbone.js, Modernizr, SVN Extended current app by developing additional functionality and engaging UI with JavaScript. Implemented significant contributions in an Agile team to achieve business goals. Reached cross-browser functionality with collaborative discussions.

Innerscope Research Inc. BOSTON, MA

Sr. Interactive Developer, L2 | 2009-2012

HTML, CSS, PHP, JavaScript, Photoshop, Illustrator

Crimson Life Sciences BOSTON, MA

Process Engineer | 2009

Java (apache.poi, javax.swing), Eclipse IDE, Microsoft Office (2001—2007), Mac and PC platforms

PROGRAMMING SKILLS

JavaScript/ES2015	EXPERIENCED
Frameworks: React/Angular/Aurelia	EXPERIENCED
CSS3/SCSS	EXPERIENCED
HTML5 experienced	EXPERIENCED
Server-side PROFICIENT	

ACTIVITIES

Co-leader of November Project Boston BOSTON, MA 2014-2015

D3.js Instructor GENERAL ASSEMBLY, MA 2015

Co-leader and Webmaster of The Most Informal Running Club Ever (TMIRCE) BOSTON, MA 2010-2011

Try out the Auction App, click through slides of its development, and read complete descriptions at evandana.com.